<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8'?><STUDY_SET>
   <STUDY accession="ERP017043" alias="ena-STUDY-DKFZ-IBIOS-06-09-2016-11:53:03:668-513" broker_name="EGA" center_name="DKFZ-IBIOS">
      <IDENTIFIERS>
         <PRIMARY_ID>ERP017043</PRIMARY_ID>
         <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="DKFZ-IBIOS">ena-STUDY-DKFZ-IBIOS-06-09-2016-11:53:03:668-513</SUBMITTER_ID>
      </IDENTIFIERS>
      <DESCRIPTOR>
         <STUDY_TITLE>Comprehensive molecular profiling identifies novel genetic drivers and subtypes underlying medulloblastoma</STUDY_TITLE>
         <STUDY_ABSTRACT>Current therapies for medulloblastoma (MB), a highly malignant childhood brain tumor, impose debilitating effects on the developing child, warranting the development of molecularly targeted treatments with reduced toxicities. Prior studies have failed to disclose the full spectrum of driver genes and molecular processes operative in MB or adequately explain heterogeneity among molecular subgroups. Herein, we detail the somatic landscape across 491 sequenced MBs and molecular heterogeneity amongst 1,256 epigenetically analyzed cases, identifying subgroup-specific mutational signatures, driver genes, and pathway alterations including previously unappreciated actionable therapeutic targets. Integrative approaches for assigning driver genes to subgroups explained >65-70% of Group 3 and Group 4, doubling previous knowledge. Novel subtypes underlying Group 3 and Group 4 were differentially enriched for specific driver events, including hotspot in-frame indels targeting KBTBD4 and ‘enhancer hijacking’ driving activation of PRDM6. Thus, application of integrative genomics to an unprecedented cohort of clinical samples derived from a single childhood cancer entity has disclosed a series of new cancer genes and biologically relevant subtype diversity that represent attractive therapeutic targets for treating MB.</STUDY_ABSTRACT>
         <STUDY_DESCRIPTION>Current therapies for medulloblastoma (MB), a highly malignant childhood brain tumor, impose debilitating effects on the developing child, warranting the development of molecularly targeted treatments with reduced toxicities. Prior studies have failed to disclose the full spectrum of driver genes and molecular processes operative in MB or adequately explain heterogeneity among molecular subgroups. Herein, we detail the somatic landscape across 491 sequenced MBs and molecular heterogeneity amongst 1,256 epigenetically analyzed cases, identifying subgroup-specific mutational signatures, driver genes, and pathway alterations including previously unappreciated actionable therapeutic targets. Integrative approaches for assigning driver genes to subgroups explained >65-70% of Group 3 and Group 4, doubling previous knowledge. Novel subtypes underlying Group 3 and Group 4 were differentially enriched for specific driver events, including hotspot in-frame indels targeting KBTBD4 and ‘enhancer hijacking’ driving activation of PRDM6. Thus, application of integrative genomics to an unprecedented cohort of clinical samples derived from a single childhood cancer entity has disclosed a series of new cancer genes and biologically relevant subtype diversity that represent attractive therapeutic targets for treating MB.</STUDY_DESCRIPTION>
         <STUDY_TYPE existing_study_type="Other"/>
      </DESCRIPTOR>
      <STUDY_LINKS>
         <STUDY_LINK>
            <XREF_LINK>
               <DB>PUBMED</DB>
               <ID>28726821</ID>
            </XREF_LINK>
         </STUDY_LINK>
      </STUDY_LINKS>
   </STUDY>
</STUDY_SET>