<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8'?><STUDY_SET>
   <STUDY alias="AML_targeted_resequencing_study-sc-2012-04-25T14:24:49Z-2188" accession="ERP001379" center_name="SC" broker_name="EGA">
      <IDENTIFIERS>
         <PRIMARY_ID>ERP001379</PRIMARY_ID>
         <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="SC">AML_targeted_resequencing_study-sc-2012-04-25T14:24:49Z-2188</SUBMITTER_ID>
      </IDENTIFIERS>
      <DESCRIPTOR>
         <STUDY_TITLE>AML_targeted_resequencing_study</STUDY_TITLE>
         <STUDY_DESCRIPTION>Genomic libraries will be generated from whole genome amplified  genomic DNA derived from 3,000 myeloid neoplasms.  Targeted capture will be performed by multiplexing 16 barcoded samples in each library.  Pools of 96 DNA samples will be subjected to 1-2 lanes of HiSeq 75bp sequencing. Reads will be mapped to the current build of the human reference genome to facilitate the generation of a comprehensive catalog of somatic mutations associated with 116 known myeloid and cancer driver genes.</STUDY_DESCRIPTION>
         <CENTER_PROJECT_NAME>AML_targeted_resequencing_study</CENTER_PROJECT_NAME>
         <STUDY_ABSTRACT>Ongoing sequencing studies are continuously defining new driver genes in myeloid malignancies (Yoshida et al, 2011; Graubert et al, 2012; Ding et al, 2012). Restricted by the availability of large and informative patient cohorts, the diagnostic and prognostic value of these findings is yet to be determined.  In a pathfinding evaluation of the prognostic value of somatic mutation status, Bejar et al analysed mutations in 18 recurrently mutated genes in 438 MDS patients and showed that patients with mutations in TP53, EZH2, ETV6, RUNX1 and ASXL1 were strong predictors of poor outcome (Bejar et al, 2011). A systematic characterisation of all genes known to be mutated in myeloid malignancies as well as some common cancer genes  across a large clinical patient cohort would deliver for the first time a comprehensive understanding of the molecular interplay of somatic mutations in myeloid disease and their individual potential as biomarkers in diagnosis and prognosis.</STUDY_ABSTRACT>
         <STUDY_TYPE existing_study_type="Cancer Genomics"/>
         <RELATED_STUDIES>
            <RELATED_STUDY>
               <RELATED_LINK>
                  <DB>PROJECT</DB>
                  <ID>2188</ID>
               </RELATED_LINK>
               <IS_PRIMARY>false</IS_PRIMARY>
            </RELATED_STUDY>
         </RELATED_STUDIES>
      </DESCRIPTOR>
   </STUDY>
</STUDY_SET>