<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8'?><STUDY_SET>
   <STUDY alias="ena-STUDY-INSERM-U674-24-01-2014-10:16:52:879-81" center_name="INSERM-U674" broker_name="EGA" accession="ERP004643">
      <IDENTIFIERS>
         <PRIMARY_ID>ERP004643</PRIMARY_ID>
         <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="INSERM-U674">ena-STUDY-INSERM-U674-24-01-2014-10:16:52:879-81</SUBMITTER_ID>
      </IDENTIFIERS>
      <DESCRIPTOR>
         <STUDY_TITLE>Integrative genomic profiling of hepatocellular adenomas reveals recurrent FRK activating mutations and mutational processes of malignant transformation</STUDY_TITLE>
         <STUDY_ABSTRACT>Hepatocellular adenomas (HCA) are benign liver tumors predominantly developed in women using oral contraception. Here, exome sequencing identified novel recurrent somatic FRK mutations that induce constitutive kinase activity, STAT3 activation and cell proliferation sensitive to Src inhibitors. We also found new recurrent mutations activating JAK1, gp130 or ß-catenin. Chromosome copy-number and methylation profiling revealed patterns that correlated with specific gene mutations and tumor phenotypes. Finally, integrative analysis of HCA transformed to hepatocellular carcinoma revealed ß-catenin mutation as an early alteration and TERT promoter mutations as associated with the last step of the adenoma-carcinoma transition. In conclusion, we identified the genomic diversity in benign hepatocyte proliferation, new therapeutic targets and the key genomic determinants of the adenoma-carcinoma transformation sequence.  Significance: Malignant transformation of benign adenoma into malignant carcinoma is frequently observed in several epithelial tumor types. Adenoma-carcinoma transition is crucial for the patient prognosis, however, little is known on the molecular mechanisms involved. Here, we performed an integrated genomic analysis of hepatocellular adenomas (HCA). Among several novel gene mutations, we identified recurrent somatic mutation activating FRK, a Src-like kinase. FRK activating mutations induce STAT3 activation and cell proliferation that can be targeted by Src inhibitors. Focusing on malignant transformation of HCA in hepatocellular carcinoma, we identified CTNNB1 and TERT promoter mutation as early and late genomic events involved in adenoma-carcinoma transition. In conclusion, we propose new therapeutic targets and an identification of adenomas with the highest risk of malignant transformation.   Highlights: - FRK is activated by somatic recurrent mutations. - FRK mutants promote cell proliferation sensitive to src inhibitors. - CTNNB1 activation is an early event in HCA transformation. - TERT promoter mutations are associated with adenoma-carcinoma transition.</STUDY_ABSTRACT>
         <STUDY_DESCRIPTION>Hepatocellular adenomas (HCA) are benign liver tumors predominantly developed in women using oral contraception. Here, exome sequencing identified novel recurrent somatic FRK mutations that induce constitutive kinase activity, STAT3 activation and cell proliferation sensitive to Src inhibitors. We also found new recurrent mutations activating JAK1, gp130 or ß-catenin. Chromosome copy-number and methylation profiling revealed patterns that correlated with specific gene mutations and tumor phenotypes. Finally, integrative analysis of HCA transformed to hepatocellular carcinoma revealed ß-catenin mutation as an early alteration and TERT promoter mutations as associated with the last step of the adenoma-carcinoma transition. In conclusion, we identified the genomic diversity in benign hepatocyte proliferation, new therapeutic targets and the key genomic determinants of the adenoma-carcinoma transformation sequence.  Significance: Malignant transformation of benign adenoma into malignant carcinoma is frequently observed in several epithelial tumor types. Adenoma-carcinoma transition is crucial for the patient prognosis, however, little is known on the molecular mechanisms involved. Here, we performed an integrated genomic analysis of hepatocellular adenomas (HCA). Among several novel gene mutations, we identified recurrent somatic mutation activating FRK, a Src-like kinase. FRK activating mutations induce STAT3 activation and cell proliferation that can be targeted by Src inhibitors. Focusing on malignant transformation of HCA in hepatocellular carcinoma, we identified CTNNB1 and TERT promoter mutation as early and late genomic events involved in adenoma-carcinoma transition. In conclusion, we propose new therapeutic targets and an identification of adenomas with the highest risk of malignant transformation.   Highlights: - FRK is activated by somatic recurrent mutations. - FRK mutants promote cell proliferation sensitive to src inhibitors. - CTNNB1 activation is an early event in HCA transformation. - TERT promoter mutations are associated with adenoma-carcinoma transition.</STUDY_DESCRIPTION>
         <CENTER_PROJECT_NAME>Hepatocellular Adenomas Integrative Genomic Profiling</CENTER_PROJECT_NAME>
         <STUDY_TYPE existing_study_type="Other"/>
      </DESCRIPTOR>
      <STUDY_LINKS>
         <STUDY_LINK>
            <XREF_LINK>
               <DB>PUBMED</DB>
               <ID>24735922</ID>
            </XREF_LINK>
         </STUDY_LINK>
      </STUDY_LINKS>
      <STUDY_ATTRIBUTES>
         <STUDY_ATTRIBUTE>
            <TAG/>
            <VALUE/>
         </STUDY_ATTRIBUTE>
      </STUDY_ATTRIBUTES>
   </STUDY>
</STUDY_SET>