<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8'?><STUDY_SET>
   <STUDY alias="ena-STUDY-SLC-05-12-2016-10:18:39:279-6" center_name="SLC" broker_name="EGA" accession="ERP020406">
      <IDENTIFIERS>
         <PRIMARY_ID>ERP020406</PRIMARY_ID>
         <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="SLC">ena-STUDY-SLC-05-12-2016-10:18:39:279-6</SUBMITTER_ID>
      </IDENTIFIERS>
      <DESCRIPTOR>
         <STUDY_TITLE>The aim of this project is to identify, on 15 French Caucasian and 10 African-Caribbean men, through an integrative approach of DNA sequencing and transciptomic analyses, relevant genomic events that characterize or allow targeting the various phenotypes of aggressiveness of early stages of prostate cancer.</STUDY_TITLE>
         <STUDY_ABSTRACT>Every year about 70,000 new cases of prostate cancer are diagnosed in France and 8,700 men died from this disease. But the incidence and the rate of mortality per 100,000 men in the French West Indies are respectively 1.5x and 2x upper than the rates observed in the metropolitan France. The aim of this project is to identify, on 15 French Caucasian and 10 African-Caribbean men, through an integrative approach of DNA sequencing and transciptomic analyses, relevant genomic events that characterize or allow targeting the various phenotypes of aggressiveness of early stages of prostate cancer.</STUDY_ABSTRACT>
         <STUDY_DESCRIPTION>Every year about 70,000 new cases of prostate cancer are diagnosed in France and 8,700 men died from this disease. But the incidence and the rate of mortality per 100,000 men in the French West Indies are respectively 1.5x and 2x upper than the rates observed in the metropolitan France. The aim of this project is to identify, on 15 French Caucasian and 10 African-Caribbean men, through an integrative approach of DNA sequencing and transciptomic analyses, relevant genomic events that characterize or allow targeting the various phenotypes of aggressiveness of early stages of prostate cancer.</STUDY_DESCRIPTION>
         <CENTER_PROJECT_NAME>Integrative approach of DNA sequencing and transciptomic analyses of 15 French Caucasian and 10 African-Caribbean men with prostate cancer.</CENTER_PROJECT_NAME>
         <STUDY_TYPE existing_study_type="Other"/>
      </DESCRIPTOR>
   </STUDY>
</STUDY_SET>