<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8'?><STUDY_SET>
   <STUDY alias="ena-STUDY-QCMG-22-02-2016-06:52:14:199-13" center_name="QCMG" broker_name="EGA" accession="ERP014328">
      <IDENTIFIERS>
         <PRIMARY_ID>ERP014328</PRIMARY_ID>
         <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="QCMG">ena-STUDY-QCMG-22-02-2016-06:52:14:199-13</SUBMITTER_ID>
      </IDENTIFIERS>
      <DESCRIPTOR>
         <STUDY_TITLE>Novel mutational mechanisms and drivers in Pancreatic Neuroendocrine Tumours</STUDY_TITLE>
         <STUDY_ABSTRACT>Pancreatic neuroendocrine tumours (PanNETs) are increasing in prevalence due to earlier detection, consequently creating challenges in clinical care, as current classification permits unsatisfactory therapeutic stratification. We performed whole genome sequencing of 102 primary PanNETs and defined the genomic events underlying their pathogenesis. We describe the mutational signatures they harbour, including a novel G:C>T:A Base-Excision-Repair-deficiency signature due to MUTYH inactivation. We uncover a larger than expected proportion of germline mutations in clinically sporadic PanNETs. These include previously unreported mutations in DNA repair genes MUTYH, CHEK2, BRCA2, and PALB2, which together with MEN1 and VHL occur in 16% of patients. Somatic mutations (point mutations and structural rearrangements) commonly occurred in genes involved in 4 main pathways: chromatin remodelling, DNA damage repair, activation of mTOR signalling (including novel EWSR1 gene fusions) and telomere maintenance. Aberrations in these mechanisms are associated with subtypes of PanNET with potential clinical application for prognostic and therapeutic stratification.</STUDY_ABSTRACT>
         <STUDY_DESCRIPTION>Pancreatic neuroendocrine tumours (PanNETs) are increasing in prevalence due to earlier detection, consequently creating challenges in clinical care, as current classification permits unsatisfactory therapeutic stratification. We performed whole genome sequencing of 102 primary PanNETs and defined the genomic events underlying their pathogenesis. We describe the mutational signatures they harbour, including a novel G:C>T:A Base-Excision-Repair-deficiency signature due to MUTYH inactivation. We uncover a larger than expected proportion of germline mutations in clinically sporadic PanNETs. These include previously unreported mutations in DNA repair genes MUTYH, CHEK2, BRCA2, and PALB2, which together with MEN1 and VHL occur in 16% of patients. Somatic mutations (point mutations and structural rearrangements) commonly occurred in genes involved in 4 main pathways: chromatin remodelling, DNA damage repair, activation of mTOR signalling (including novel EWSR1 gene fusions) and telomere maintenance. Aberrations in these mechanisms are associated with subtypes of PanNET with potential clinical application for prognostic and therapeutic stratification.</STUDY_DESCRIPTION>
         <CENTER_PROJECT_NAME>ICGC Pancreatic Neuroendocrine project</CENTER_PROJECT_NAME>
         <STUDY_TYPE existing_study_type="Other"/>
      </DESCRIPTOR>
   </STUDY>
</STUDY_SET>