<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8'?><STUDY_SET>
   <STUDY alias="ena-STUDY-OICR_ICGC-27-11-2015-12:18:41:489-212" center_name="OICR_ICGC" broker_name="EGA" accession="ERP013330">
      <IDENTIFIERS>
         <PRIMARY_ID>ERP013330</PRIMARY_ID>
         <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="OICR_ICGC">ena-STUDY-OICR_ICGC-27-11-2015-12:18:41:489-212</SUBMITTER_ID>
      </IDENTIFIERS>
      <DESCRIPTOR>
         <STUDY_TITLE>MED12L Gene Alterations Define Aggressive BRCA2-Mutant Prostate Cancers</STUDY_TITLE>
         <STUDY_ABSTRACT>Germline mutation of BRCA2 increases the lifetime risk of developing prostate cancer (PCa) by over 700%. BRCA2-mutant PCa have poorer prognosis than sporadic PCa, with rapid development of metastatic, castrate-resistant prostate cancer (mCRPC) and 5-year cancer-specific survival rates of ~50-60%1-4. Despite this, unique genomic driver events that explain the aggressiveness of localized BRCA2-mutant PCa are lacking. We used whole-genome sequencing to fully characterize 14 BRCA2-mutant PCa and demonstrate that BRCA2-mutant PCa is associated with increased genetic instability and a mutually exclusive mutational burden when compared to sporadic PCa. Importantly, BRCA2-mutated cancers are defined by unique copy number gains and hypomethylation events, including alterations in the MED12L/MED12 axis, which are found solely in mCRPC and are enriched in PCa tumours harbouring aggressive intraductal carcinoma (IDC-P) pathologic sub-types. Our findings begin to explain the clinical entity of BRCA2-mutated PCa as these tumours have a unique and aggressive genotype de novo, associated with IDC-P and mCRPC, even in the hormone-naive setting.</STUDY_ABSTRACT>
         <STUDY_DESCRIPTION>Germline mutation of BRCA2 increases the lifetime risk of developing prostate cancer (PCa) by over 700%. BRCA2-mutant PCa have poorer prognosis than sporadic PCa, with rapid development of metastatic, castrate-resistant prostate cancer (mCRPC) and 5-year cancer-specific survival rates of ~50-60%1-4. Despite this, unique genomic driver events that explain the aggressiveness of localized BRCA2-mutant PCa are lacking. We used whole-genome sequencing to fully characterize 14 BRCA2-mutant PCa and demonstrate that BRCA2-mutant PCa is associated with increased genetic instability and a mutually exclusive mutational burden when compared to sporadic PCa. Importantly, BRCA2-mutated cancers are defined by unique copy number gains and hypomethylation events, including alterations in the MED12L/MED12 axis, which are found solely in mCRPC and are enriched in PCa tumours harbouring aggressive intraductal carcinoma (IDC-P) pathologic sub-types. Our findings begin to explain the clinical entity of BRCA2-mutated PCa as these tumours have a unique and aggressive genotype de novo, associated with IDC-P and mCRPC, even in the hormone-naive setting.</STUDY_DESCRIPTION>
         <STUDY_TYPE existing_study_type="Other"/>
      </DESCRIPTOR>
   </STUDY>
</STUDY_SET>