<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8'?><STUDY_SET>
   <STUDY alias="ena-STUDY-BGI-16-07-2014-09:33:19:613-515" center_name="BGI" broker_name="EGA" accession="ERP006356">
      <IDENTIFIERS>
         <PRIMARY_ID>ERP006356</PRIMARY_ID>
         <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="BGI">ena-STUDY-BGI-16-07-2014-09:33:19:613-515</SUBMITTER_ID>
      </IDENTIFIERS>
      <DESCRIPTOR>
         <STUDY_TITLE>65 prostate cancer cases WGS and transcriptome sequencing project</STUDY_TITLE>
         <STUDY_ABSTRACT>We obtained whole-genome and transcriptome sequencing of tumor-benign pairs from 65 Asian prostate cancer (PCa) patients. Taken together with the TCGA PCa cohort, our integration analysis provides the first comprehensive mutational landscape of PCas across major ethnics worldwide and reveals potential novel role of frequent altered chromatin remodeler genes in PCas without androgen receptor (AR) alteration and complex rearrangements derived from Chromoplexy. In addition, we identified 5 putative tumor suppressor genes (TSGs) chains including one on chromosome 13q with novel findings of PCDH9 (deletions in 15/65 tumors) which was implicated in aggressive progression of prostate cancer. Finally, the integrative pathway and co-expression network analysis followed by the functional study indicated the frequent altered genes, particularly focal amplifications of PLXNA1 (11/65), in semaphoring signaling of axon guidance pathway may interact with PI3K/AKT and AR signaling and also contribute to the aggressiveness and progression of prostate cancer.</STUDY_ABSTRACT>
         <STUDY_DESCRIPTION>We obtained whole-genome and transcriptome sequencing of tumor-benign pairs from 65 Asian prostate cancer (PCa) patients. Taken together with the TCGA PCa cohort, our integration analysis provides the first comprehensive mutational landscape of PCas across major ethnics worldwide and reveals potential novel role of frequent altered chromatin remodeler genes in PCas without androgen receptor (AR) alteration and complex rearrangements derived from Chromoplexy. In addition, we identified 5 putative tumor suppressor genes (TSGs) chains including one on chromosome 13q with novel findings of PCDH9 (deletions in 15/65 tumors) which was implicated in aggressive progression of prostate cancer. Finally, the integrative pathway and co-expression network analysis followed by the functional study indicated the frequent altered genes, particularly focal amplifications of PLXNA1 (11/65), in semaphoring signaling of axon guidance pathway may interact with PI3K/AKT and AR signaling and also contribute to the aggressiveness and progression of prostate cancer.</STUDY_DESCRIPTION>
         <CENTER_PROJECT_NAME>Integration analyses reveal frequent aberrations in chromatin remodeling and axon guidance pathway and their novel implications in prostate cancer</CENTER_PROJECT_NAME>
         <STUDY_TYPE existing_study_type="Other"/>
      </DESCRIPTOR>
   </STUDY>
</STUDY_SET>