<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8'?><STUDY_SET>
   <STUDY alias="ena-STUDY-DKFZ-IBIOS-20-03-2015-12:32:08:389-558" center_name="DKFZ-IBIOS" broker_name="EGA" accession="ERP009943">
      <IDENTIFIERS>
         <PRIMARY_ID>ERP009943</PRIMARY_ID>
         <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="DKFZ-IBIOS">ena-STUDY-DKFZ-IBIOS-20-03-2015-12:32:08:389-558</SUBMITTER_ID>
      </IDENTIFIERS>
      <DESCRIPTOR>
         <STUDY_TITLE>MINCR is a MYC-induced lncRNA able to modulate MYC’s transcriptional network in Burkitt lymphoma cells</STUDY_TITLE>
         <STUDY_ABSTRACT>Despite the established role of the transcription factor MYC in cancer, little is known about the involvement of lncRNAs in mediating MYC’s function. Here we have intersected RNA-sequencing data from MYC-inducible cell lines, from a cohort of 91 mature B-cell lymphomas and from sorted germinal-center B-cells. By this approach, we identified 13 lncRNAs differentially expressed in IG-MYC-positive Burkitt lymphoma and regulated by MYC in the model cell lines. Among them we focused on a lncRNA that we named MINCR, showing a strong correlation with MYC expression in MYC-positive lymphomas and in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinomas. RNAi experiments showed that MINCR controls cellular viability by influencing the expression of MYC-regulated cell cycle genes. Finally we provide evidences that down-regulation of AURKA, AURKB and CTD1 may explain the reduction in cellular proliferation observed upon MINCR knock-down. We therefore suggest that MINCR acts as a modulator of MYC transcriptional control of cell cycle genes.</STUDY_ABSTRACT>
         <STUDY_DESCRIPTION>Despite the established role of the transcription factor MYC in cancer, little is known about the involvement of lncRNAs in mediating MYC’s function. Here we have intersected RNA-sequencing data from MYC-inducible cell lines, from a cohort of 91 mature B-cell lymphomas and from sorted germinal-center B-cells. By this approach, we identified 13 lncRNAs differentially expressed in IG-MYC-positive Burkitt lymphoma and regulated by MYC in the model cell lines. Among them we focused on a lncRNA that we named MINCR, showing a strong correlation with MYC expression in MYC-positive lymphomas and in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinomas. RNAi experiments showed that MINCR controls cellular viability by influencing the expression of MYC-regulated cell cycle genes. Finally we provide evidences that down-regulation of AURKA, AURKB and CTD1 may explain the reduction in cellular proliferation observed upon MINCR knock-down. We therefore suggest that MINCR acts as a modulator of MYC transcriptional control of cell cycle genes.</STUDY_DESCRIPTION>
         <CENTER_PROJECT_NAME>ramses-2015-02-05</CENTER_PROJECT_NAME>
         <STUDY_TYPE existing_study_type="Other"/>
      </DESCRIPTOR>
   </STUDY>
</STUDY_SET>