<?xml version = '1.0' encoding = 'UTF-8'?><STUDY_SET>
   <STUDY alias="ena-STUDY-NIBMG-03-11-2014-12:27:41:397-617" center_name="NIBMG" broker_name="EGA" accession="ERP008590">
      <IDENTIFIERS>
         <PRIMARY_ID>ERP008590</PRIMARY_ID>
         <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="NIBMG">ena-STUDY-NIBMG-03-11-2014-12:27:41:397-617</SUBMITTER_ID>
      </IDENTIFIERS>
      <DESCRIPTOR>
         <STUDY_TITLE>Genomic Alterations in Gingivo-buccal Cancer: ICGC-India Project_YR02</STUDY_TITLE>
         <STUDY_ABSTRACT>As a part of the ICGC, India has undertaken genomic studies on gingivobuccal cancer of the oral cavity, which is the most prevalent form of cancer among men in India. There are various known environmental (life-style) correlates of this cancer, the most important of which are tobacco chewing and HPV infection.  Paired DNA samples – isolated from the tumour tissue and from the blood of fifty six patients – have been analyzed to catalog germline and somatic mutations. Association between each observed genomic alteration and exposure to environmental risk factors is being explored.
Detailed clinical characterization of the patients, collection of data on demographic and environmental exposures, and isolation of DNA samples from blood and tumour tissues collected from each patient are being done at the Advanced Centre for Research, Treatment and Education on Cancer, Mumbai. Exome capture and deep resequencing are being performed at the National Institute of Biomedical Genomics, Kalyani. We have analyzed the exomes of paired blood and tumour DNA samples using exome capture by Illumina TrueSeq Exome Enrichment kit followed by sequencing on Illumina HiSeq-2000. Each exome is being sequenced at a mean depth of 70x for Tumour  and 40x  for Blood. In addition, we have used Illumina Omni 2.5 SNP-chips to generate genotype data.</STUDY_ABSTRACT>
         <STUDY_DESCRIPTION>As a part of the ICGC, India has undertaken genomic studies on gingivobuccal cancer of the oral cavity, which is the most prevalent form of cancer among men in India. There are various known environmental (life-style) correlates of this cancer, the most important of which are tobacco chewing and HPV infection.  Paired DNA samples – isolated from the tumour tissue and from the blood of fifty six patients – have been analyzed to catalog germline and somatic mutations. Association between each observed genomic alteration and exposure to environmental risk factors is being explored.
Detailed clinical characterization of the patients, collection of data on demographic and environmental exposures, and isolation of DNA samples from blood and tumour tissues collected from each patient are being done at the Advanced Centre for Research, Treatment and Education on Cancer, Mumbai. Exome capture and deep resequencing are being performed at the National Institute of Biomedical Genomics, Kalyani. We have analyzed the exomes of paired blood and tumour DNA samples using exome capture by Illumina TrueSeq Exome Enrichment kit followed by sequencing on Illumina HiSeq-2000. Each exome is being sequenced at a mean depth of 70x for Tumour  and 40x  for Blood. In addition, we have used Illumina Omni 2.5 SNP-chips to generate genotype data.</STUDY_DESCRIPTION>
         <CENTER_PROJECT_NAME>ICGC_INDIAPROJECT_2</CENTER_PROJECT_NAME>
         <STUDY_TYPE existing_study_type="Other"/>
      </DESCRIPTOR>
   </STUDY>
</STUDY_SET>